

# ABOUT ME

I am a 22 year-old software engineer and self-taught designer that loves to design and build products that solve challenging world-scale problems with careful user research, design, planning and strong engineering principles. I have a sharp eye for pixel-perfect detail.

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

### **FRONTEND**

REACT + REDUX	••••
ANGULAR, RAILS	••••
JAVASCRIPT, JQUERY	••••
HTML5, CSS3, SCSS	••••
BACKEND	
MYSQL/SQL	••••
NODE.JS + EXPRESS	••••
MONGODB, FIREBASE	••••
PHP	••••
PROGRAMMING	
C/C++	••••
C#, ROBOTC, RUBY	•••00
JAVA	••••
PYTHON	••••
MOBILE DEVELOPMENT	

### **PLATFORMS / TOOLS**

ADOBE PHOTOSHOP

ADOBE ILLUSTRATOR

**ANDROID** 

**SKETCHUP** 

**DESIGN & CAD** 

GIT, JIRA, SELENIUM, WEBPACK CUCUMBER, AWS, DOCKER, JETBRAINS

# MAYANK BANSAL

# Full Stack Engineer + Designer

manky.bansal@gmail.com

https://manky.me

Seattle, Washington

**+**1 (312) 593-2465

## **EDUCATION**



ILLINOIS INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY 2017 - 2018, Chicago, Illinois

3.65/4.00 GPA, B.S. Computer Science

Dean's List, Cum Laude, Merit Scholarship, Finished Early

# WORK EXPERIENCE

## 2018 - PRESENT

LEGALPAD, INC.

### **Frontend Engineer**

Worked on designing and implementing the consumer-facing part of Legalpad's H-1B automation and support software and improved the UI and UX of the internal operator and support tools.

WWW.LEGALPAD.IO

#### 2011 - PRESENT

MITRAZ FINANCIAL, PVT. LTD.

### **Contract Developer & Designer**

Worked on contract design projects, mobile platform apps and web projects. Designed the current UI language and product identity.

WWW.MITRAZ.FINANCIAL

## 2016 - 2017

CASANYLA, PVT. LTD.

# **Frontend Developer**

Designed and developed their website, backend platform & built tools to identify styles users like based on interests.

WWW.CASANYLA.COM

## **PROJECTS**

#### 2017

CHUTTA - ANGELHACK

### Concept, Frontend Developer

Built the consumer facing platform for a live proof of concept transactional microsaving and auto-investing service that works with all major Indian banks which placed 2nd in the AH10 AngelHack Bangalore.

WWW.MANKY.ME/CHUTTA

## 2012 - 2015 **LIBRORUM**

## Co-Founder, Full Stack Engineer

Built an online community sharing platform for physical house-hold objects to encourage lending & borrowing in residential layouts.

WWW.MANKY.ME/LIBRORUM

## 2012 - 2017

SADGI CREATIVE

#### Co-Founder, Full Stack Engineer

Worked on and supervised multiple client projects involving graphic design, server management, frontend & backend development.

WWW.MANKY.ME/SADGI

# HONORS & AWARDS

HONORS **CUM LAUDE ILLINOIS TECH** 

2018

**RUNNER UP DESIGNATHON MIT MANIPAL** 2016

**RUNNER UP** ANGELHACK '17 **BANGALORE** 

2017

**RUNNER UP** CODE HEAT '16 **MIT MANIPAL** 2016

**BEST USE OF BACKEND TECH** SCARLETHACKS '17

**MAJOR LEAGUE HACKING** 

2017

NATIONAL FINALIST

MICROSOFT HACKATHON **MICROSOFT IDC** 

2015





••••

 $\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ$ 

 $\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ$ 

